Ryan J. Skelly

ryan@iatek.com, ris1070@wildcats.unh.edu, ryanskelly.com, linkedin.com/in/ryan-j-skelly/

Portsmouth, RI & Durham, NH (401) 864-5571

Profile:

I am an outgoing, hardworking, and determined individual. From a young age, I've always been interested into getting into Software Development field. Natural Intuition and years of practice serve me well at my current employer, the UNH IOL. Abstraction and Critical Thinking help allow me to solve development and network related roadblocks I encounter. I also have experience coding in both a front and backend context, along with Industry-Standard Libraries and Frameworks. My recent interests include, Kubernetes, Docker, Virtualization, DevSecOps and Cloud Computing. I am currently an Information Technology Major (B.S.), with a minor in Analytics at the University of New Hampshire.

Education:

- > University Of New Hampshire (2019-2023) > Web Development
- > BS Information Technology Major, **Analytics Minor**
 - Computer/OS Design - Networking Infrastructures
 - Software & Web - Database Operations Development
 - Cyber Security - Clean Code Philosophy
 - Data Structures - Complex Problem Solving
- > Portsmouth High School (2015-2019)

Experience:

- > InterOperability Laboratory (2020-Present)
- > Test Technician & Software Dev.

- IPv6 - VCenter VM - Agile Development Protocols Control

- Device - Customer - Network Management Design Support

- > Aquidneck Pizza (2019-2020)
- > Pizza Delivery, Gen. Assistant
- > 15 Point Rd Restaurant (2016-2019)
- > Busser

- - HTML/XML - Javascript/ReactJS - CSS
 - Bootstrap - RESTful API
- > Networking

Skills:

- Device/Network - IPv4 & v6 **Protocols** Configuration

- Packet Capture - Network Admin. **Analysis**

- Server - AWS Deployment Management & Monitoring

- > Software Development
 - Python - Typescript

- SQL/MySQL - C/C++

- Atlassian Dev. - Version Ctrl. (Git/Svn) **Platform**

Hobbies & Interests:

- Outdoors - Hiking - Camping

- Video - PC - Web3/DeFi Games Building